Lavina Khushlani Software Engineer

Versatile and dedicated full stack software engineer with 2.10+ years of industry experience in object oriented programming (OOP) using Python. Self-directed leader with expertise in Django, Angular, Data Analysis, NLP. I can quickly learn and master new technologies. I also love solving problems on various competitive programming platforms.

Work History

2021-05-Current

Software Engineer Associate

JP Morgan and Chase, India, Bengaluru, Karnataka

Recently joined the organization currently woking on **Pandas**, **Numpy** and **React** based applications.

2018-07 – 2021-04

Software Engineer

HSBC Technology India, Pune, Maharashtra

- Achieved a reduction in Service Requests by 47% in issue tracking tool
 JIRA using NLP and jira-python API. Implemented Cosine Similarity and
 TF-IDF to find top three similar jiras and commented on new jira as
 ready references. Used flask as backend and webhooks for event
 listener
- Developed RESTful web-application in Angular, Django supporting CRUD operations, also implemented the Maker Checker functionalties thus maintaining access control. The dashboard also maintains the audit trail of the users making the change.
- Developed asynchronous framework and microcervices based architecture using OOP in python. Worked on alerting mechnanisms in case of failures (Email Alerting using SMTP) and log monitoring on ELK; developed Kafka's functionality inhouse.
- Implemented the processing of 80k records in around 5 seconds which was earlier taking taking 5 to 6 mins using **multiprocessing** with pandas and regular expressions.
- Saved time to login to servers to check the running processes.
 Developed a Process Monitoring web-app using django angular7 and Postgres Sql, deployed using Nginx (used as a reverse proxy) and Gunicorn. The dashboard monitors which processes are active in shell and which are not using the process ids.
- Achieved cost saving of 3 FTEs by automating the manual Reconcliation process. Optimised Subset-Sum algorithm using generators and used it in developing one-many rule-based amount netting algorithms.
- Automated NAS Disaster Recovery Mechanism using shell scripting, the service switches to contingeny NAS in case of failures and keeps application running

Certifications

2020-05	Google Cloud Platform: Core Infrastructure (Coursera)
2020-04	Essential Google Cloud Infrastructure: Foundation (Coursera)
2020-04	Essential google cloud infrastructure: Core Services (Coursera)
2018-11	Python for Data Science and Machine Learning (Udemy)
2017-07	Design and analysis of algorithms (IIT Madras)
2016-06	Python Programing

Education

2014 - 2018 Bachelors of Technology: Computer Science

GLA University - Mathura GPA: 8.1

Contact

Phone

8534921400

F-mail

lavinakhushlani@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/lavina-khushlani-1331b6114/

Personal projects on Github: https://github.com/LKhushlani/

Skills

Backend: Python, Django, Django ORM, Flask, Shell scripting, Java

Front end: Angular, HTML, CSS, JavaScript.

Version Control and other tools: Git, JIRA, ELK, dkron

Databases PostgresSql, MySQL

Libraries: Beautiful Soup, Exchange API, jira-python, cx_oracle, Unittest, Tesseract OCR, config parsers, SMTP Lib

Other interests: Experience in Natural Language Processing, Data Analysis using Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib, Competitive Coding. Sound knowledge of various Data Structures and Algorithms.

Methodologies: Agile Scrum, worked through the entire lifecycle of the projects including Requirement gathering, Design , Development, Deployment, Testing and Support.

Soft Skills:

- problem solving
- teamwork
- written/oral communication
- leadership